I am not the first of my kind.
ADA：我不是我种族中的第一人
Hello, agents. I'm Susanna Moyer and this is the ingress report
各位特工们大家好 我是 Susanna Moyer 这里是本周的 Ingress Report
When the Anti-Magnus leader Jahan,
当反马格纳斯（Anti-Magnus）运动领袖 Jahan
try to activate 30 Magnus *nest* during Shonin
试图在证人异常期间激活 13 Magnus 组织的一个巢穴的时候
A massive XM eruption*ensute*
一场大规模的 XM 爆发随之发生
At that moment
在那个时候
nearly every known researcher associate with the Niantic project.
几乎每一个已知的和 Niantic 计划有关的研究者
people like Martin Schubert, Devra Bogdanovich Oliver Lynton-Wolfel
比如 Martin Schubert、Devra Bogdanovich、Oliver Lynton-Wolfel
and Stein Lightman instantly disappeared.
和 Stein Lightman 都立刻消失了
and have since began to appear in the port network one by one.
并自此一个接一个出现在 Portal 网络中
Now Jahan is attempting to activate another ancient site.
现在 Jahan 正试图激活另一个古代遗址――
This one lies below the historic city of Persepolis
这个遗址存在于历史悠久的古城波斯波利斯之下 【波斯波利斯：波斯阿黑门尼德王朝的第二个都城，位于伊朗扎格罗斯山区】
which some say was destroyed to conceal the great power hidden beneath it.
据说此地当初是因为要封存藏于在此之下的巨大力量而被毁的
Jahan believed that *nezia* technology located there
Jahan相信 N’zeer 的科技就在那里
could solve many of humanitie's ills. But after what happened during Shonin,
这种科技能够解决诸多人性的顽疾 但在证人异常事件之后
many worry that she will only create more chaos.
很多人都担心她只会制造更多的混乱
Hank Johnson had been one of the most vocal critics of Jahan's plans
Hank Johnson 一直是 Jahan 计划最主要的反对者之一
He had previously promised to travel to Persepolis
他曾经许诺前往波斯波利斯
confront her and prevent her from activating this ancient power.
与她对峙并阻止该计划 以防这股古老的力量被唤醒
a recent video however leaked from the net of the *nomat shoot*
一份最近从 Nomad 系列节目泄露的视频文件 【Nomad：由Hank Johnson主持的节目，内容与Ingress主线内容相关】
appears to show no other than Devra Bogdanovich appearing before him
刚好说明在他之前除了 Devra Bogdanovich 没有任何人去过那里
and warning him not to go there for his own safety.
并警告他 为了他个人的安全不要前往那里
*conqueror*
“不要去 Hank”
*Do not go to Persepolis ever* *We will be played in their hands*
“不要去波斯波利斯 绝不”
as of now it unclear whether Hank Johnson intends to heed her advice.
而现在并不清楚 Hank Johnson 会不会听取此建议
*To add to this*, a few weeks ago agents in Washington DC
作为补充 几周前 华盛顿的特工们
gave me a letter from my father containing a message constructed in glyphs
给了我一封来自我父亲的信 信中有一条由符文（Glyph）写成的消息
I was able to translate it with the help of *operation expandor*
I was able to translate it with the help of operation Essex founder 在 Essex 组织创始人 Edgar Allan Wright 博士的帮助下 我得以翻译此条符文 【Essex组织: 召集玩家调查Niantic计划的秘密的组织，有官方支持，G+有相关页面 】
intelligent *discover* unbound future create answer.
“智能会发现无限可能的未来，创造答案”
while the true nature of this message remains complexing,
而这条信息的真正含义还尚不清楚
I am grateful to all those in DC who helped safety relay it to me,
我很感谢华盛顿的特工 他们安全地把这条信息交给了我
and to *AndrewKrug* behind the scanner providing footage of the exchange.
还有感谢 Behind The Scanner 栏目的 Andrew Krug 为我提供此次交换的视频片段
be sure to tune into behind the scanner this evening on their YouTube channel.
今晚请一定去收看他们 YouTube 频道的 Behind The Scanner 栏目
despite the many unknowns it clear that when the factions collide this weekend
尽管很多事情尚未明了 但我们很清楚当这个周末两个阵营激战之时
the fated of the great researcher Stein Lightman will be decided.
符文研究者 Stein Lightman 的命运将被裁决
it is likely that the outcome of the anomaly will also have a direct effect
与此同时 此次异常活动的结果也会直接影响到 Jahan 的尝试――
to reactivate the acient "nezia* technology buried below Persepolis.
她企图重新激活在波斯波利斯之下埋藏的古老 N’zeer 科技
the Lightman Shards has been *circling* the globe for over a month now,
Lightman 碎片已经环游世界一个多月了
engaging agent in a high-stakes struggle wherever they go
不论碎片去往哪里 特工们都需要保持高度警惕
from Sri Lanka reporter *overseed* a four-day standoff for control of the
来自斯里兰卡的记者见证了一场长达四天的僵局
Shards #8 #9 and #39 which arrived there from Malaysia
为了争夺来自于马来西亚的碎片 #8 #9 和 #39 的控制权
over 100 ressistance members including
一百余名反抗军成员参与此役
*simphyes, cc89, ultrastrike,
包括 @simfyz @cc89 @U1traStrike @NeonPanther
and tompoo* were able to successfully transport the shards
和 @TomBull 得以成功地分批
in lebanon agents *fallfallen, puppyshar,
在黎巴嫩 特工 @Foulfoulen @papashark
artirohan* and dozens of other enlighted
@rtrohan @Skykiller 以及一些其他启蒙军
*patched* a plan to rescue Shard #11 from a island of *CenturyTel*
策划了一个把碎片 #11 从 Centrolene 火山岛上营救出来的计划
where it had remained unclaimed since the shard first spot.
该岛自从碎片第一次现身起就处于未被占领状态
By sending the agent *Fallfallen*
通过派遣特工 @Foulfoulen
to the Greek islands they were able to extract the Shard into lebanon.
去了希腊群岛 他们在那里获得碎片并运往黎巴嫩
where an extended battle against the resistance began.
而在黎巴嫩 一场与反抗军的战斗开始了
Ultimately resistance agent including fatfood, moodrumy
最终反抗军特工们 包括 @fadfoud @modrami
and spyrose were able to take control of the Shard and safely transporedt it to Riyadh.
和 @spyr0s 得以控制住碎片 并安全地把它转移到了利雅得
in addition agency of both factions in Singapore, China, Vietnam and Malaysia and Taiwan
此外在新加坡、中国、越南、马来西亚和台湾的双方阵营的特工
works tiredlessly for days in an attempt to gain control of Shards #9, #17 and #39.
不顾疲倦地奋战了好几天 为了尝试保持对碎片 #9 #17 和 #39 的控制权
*sit right emerging*but it seems clear that hunderds if not thounds of
大海阻碍了现有的调动 但很明显有成百上千的
both enlighted and ressitance agents were involed
反抗军和启蒙军的特工参与进了
ultimately those Shards traveld on a direct link from Vietnam to
最终那些碎片通过一条从越南直抵反抗军目的地的 Link
the ressistance target in keelung city.
到达了基隆市
agent *puppyChenTW, parseofheaven,
特工 @puppyChenTW @cass @ annacomic 等是参与此行动的很多特工中的几个
at of this weekend, the enlightened control 8
这周末 启蒙军控制了
of the lightmen Shards to 3 of the resistance.
Lightman 碎片中的8个 相比下反抗军只控制了3个
Going into the Persepolis fnale
日渐临近波斯波利斯的结局
resistant lead the series with a thin margin
反抗军以微弱的优势暂时领先整个系列活动
of 10157 to 9879
比分是 10157 比 9879
The Persepolis fnale anomalies will take place on June 28 in Tohoku
波斯波利斯异常的终章将开始于六月二十八日在仙台 顶端注释【Tohoku直译是东北，为仙台市代称】
Utrecht and Portland with with sitellites in Jakarta, Perth
乌德勒支和波特兰，以及在雅加达、珀斯 顶端注释【乌得勒支：荷兰城市 】
Liverpool, Poznan, Helsinki Milwaukee
利物浦、波兹南、赫尔辛基、密尔沃基 【波兹南：波兰城市 密尔沃基：美国威斯康星州城市】
Nashyille and Ft. Collins
纳什维尔和科林斯堡 【纳什维尔：美国田纳西州首府 科林斯堡：科罗拉多州城市】
In portland Agents will also be able to take part
在波特兰 特工们为了各个阵营的利益
in a physically and mentally demanding
还将参加一场需要体力和智力的
I will be in Utrecht to monitor the anomaly from the ground
我会在乌德勒支地面指挥这次的异常活动
and I look forward to seeing many of you there.
而且我希望能在那里看到你们大家
in the past few days
过去的几天里
P. A. Chapeau had reported that Klue,
P.A.Chapeau 报道说
following here successful separation from A.D.A have gone missing.
Klue 成功地从 ADA 分离出去 随之失去了踪迹
initially the circumstances of her disappearance was unclear.
最开始她失踪的状况却无人知晓
but it now appears that she is "on root" to the anomaly in Potland.
但是现在 她似乎已经在前往波特兰的异常活动的路途中
she'd previously appeared there following operation *time zero*
她曾经出现在零点（Time Zero）行动中
and was deeply affected by the XM anomaly that happened then
并且深受随后发生的 XM 异常的影响
it is unclear whether Klue to travel to Portland is of her own volition
我们并不清楚 Klue 是不是基于她自身的意愿前往波特兰
and will this anomaly have the same effect on her as it did last time.
也不清楚这次的异常事件会不会对她有像上次一样的影响
agent. Much rest *sem* *will unfold* in the next few days.
特工们 留给我们休息的时间只有短短几天
the Lightning Shards will take their final journey and
Lightman 碎片将开启他们最后的旅程
thousands will meet in anomaly zones to fight for their faction and their beliefs.
数千名特工将在异常区域兵戎相见 为了他们的阵营和信仰而奋战
I will all of you good luck in what's to come
我祝愿你们在接下来的活动中好运
for the ingress report I'm Susanna Moyer
这里是 Ingress Report 我是 Susanna Moyer
the past *once eclispe* the present
ADA：过去的阴影曾经遮蔽了现在
now that will change
现在 它会改变